SHUAIBU BABA AHMED

+2349021611147 shuaibuahmed5@gmail.com No2 Ali Gantsa Street Mariri Faraway New Layout, Kano.

Profile Summary

Well driven and goal-oriented IT Specialist with years of experience with a wide variety of professional experience, passionate about information technology and educating the next generation of technology users and innovators.

Date of Birth: 11th January 1996

Nationality: Nigerian Sex: Male

State of Origin: Bauchi State Languages: English, Hausa

Marital status: Single

WORK EXPERIENCE

Exaro Enterprise Solutions, Bauchi, Nigeria. April 2021 – Date *System Administrator*

- Assisted configuring networking equipment both ethernet and WI-FI
- Providing help desk support to end-users, including troubleshooting, server support and customer service
- Training users and agents how to use software and applications
- Managing and maintaining hardware inventory
- Managing network performance through monitoring and app prioritization.

Bauchi State Health Contributory Management Agency (BASHCMA), Bauchi, Nigeria. March – May 2021

Enrollment Officer

• Enrollment of Basic Health Care Provision Fund (BHCPF) vulnerable into National Health Insurance (NHIS) database

National Agency for Food and Drug Administration and Control (NAFDAC), Kano, Nigeria. November 2019- November 2020

National Youth Service Corps (NYSC) IT Intern

- Consulted and translated actual databases into new platform as well backing up data during process
- Installation and maintenance of hardware and software
- Diagnosed successfully and resolved hardware and software issues on user workstation and devices

• Fulfilled general duties such as checking, verifying and processing client's data and information

Romi Kitchen Pride, Kano, Nigeria. 2019 - 2020

Store Manager

- Website design, creation and maintenance.
- Inventory management.
- Customer service

Ralph soft and co Dubai, UAE. May 2019 - August 2019

Frontend design intern

- Interactive user centered designs delivering innovative concepts, wireframes, low and high fidelity
- Developed user interfaces and interaction flows of a health software application
- Logo design

Management Edge Abuja, Nigeria. July 2018 - August 2018 IT Intern

- Assisted in installation and configuration of security cameras
- Assisted in installation and maintenance of network peripherals
- Designed new Logos, Flyers, ads and banners for upcoming promotions increasing page visit
- Installed and maintained hardware and software components on computer stations and IT equipment
- Data Entry for clients Admin Panel

Independent National Electoral commission (INEC) Kano, Nigeria. June 2017 - August 2017

IT Intern

- Data collection from multiple sources and stored into a single location ensuring the information is stored effectively and securely in the main server to enable effective data analysis
- Handled support tickets with software and hardware, evaluated, determined root cause and collaborated with technical support to ensure 100% problem resolution
- Registered new voters and updated existing ones
- Storing information and backing it up on the system
- · Maintaining and updating the database

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology New York, Dubai campus.

B.Sc. (Hons) Computer in Information Technology (2019)

Air Force Military School Jos Nigeria.

Senior Secondary School Certificate (2012)

Yanduste Nursery and Primary School, kano Nigeria.

Primary School Certificate (2006)

ADDITIONAL TRAINING/CERTIFICATIONS

National Youth Service Corps. (2020)

Diploma in Information Technology Training Hand on Information Technology, Kano Nigeria. (2013)

Certificate in Information Technology Training Hands on Information Technology, Kano Nigeria. (2009)

PROJECTS

RAPIDS CEMETERY 2018

Worked with a local non-profit organization to gather requirements for an application that will help encourage people to visit a local cemetery in addition to the other historical locations in the area.

Designed and implemented the database for the project (MySQL). Our sponsors would like to create an experience where the users can interact with the area and learn about the people, native plants, and other events that have and will occur in the area. Next semester we will build these applications and compete with other teams for a chance to be selected as the project our sponsors will implement.

SKILLS

Hardware

Assembly, Maintenance, Drivers and Troubleshooting

Software Applications

Installation, Adobe XD, VM Ware, Wireshark

Operating Systems

Microsoft windows, MacOS, Linux

Networks

Configuration, Servers, Routers, LAN Technology

Security

Virus protection, Maintenance, Monitoring, Backup Management

Programming Languages

Python, Django, JavaScript, CSS

General skills

Problem solving, Teamwork, Communication

HOBBIES & INTERESTS:

Gaming, Football and Blockchain Technology

REFERENCES

DR Mansur Mustapha Dada Bauchi State Health Contributory Management Agency 08034508669

Ralph Vreman Ralphsoft and co Rvreman@ralphsoft.com

Air Commodore AT Baba (RTD) No 2 Ali Gantsa street faraway new layout Kano 08035905485